my problems yeah yeah that's a good
question well all the problems can be
solved if you see that all problems are
caused by craving for which you're
responsible there's no problem if there
isn't suffering but rather when there is
a problem means that something is a
problem because it's making you suffer
well headache in itself it's not a
problem nor is it a suffering you're not
wanting it to be that way and not
wanting to have a headache while having
or not having headache is not in your
control that's why you suffer so you
crave to get rid of the circumstances
that you find displeasing which means
you create a problem that's what I mean
at the root of every suffering is
craving it's impossible to experience
suffering without having the present
craving present in your experience as
your attitude it's impossible that's why
the Buddha said that the root of
suffering is craving not the external
circumstances however bad they might be
so being in poverty poverty is not
suffering poverty is hardship but
hardship does not need to be suffering
if you don't basically again in a
fundamental on a fundamental level if
you want to describe the nature of
Cravens there's these three types when
when circumstances are pleasing your
craving for more of that pleasure
the circumstances are displeasing you
are craving for that displeasure to
disappear to not be there you want to
get rid of it instantly and the third
type is the surface to see but basically
the circumstances are neither good nor
bad you kind of crave towards indolence and
you kind of crave towards indolence and
searching excitement or whatever but
people people people fear border they
they fear the like a neutral environment
which is neither good nor bad they can't
recognize it as peaceful so in that in
the very manner person is fully
responsible for all of the suffering
that he experienced in his life because
there was the human case in the suitors
that the Buddha was giving the example
was the even if a highway robbers attack
you and sever you limb by limb and
torture you that basically won't be the
suffering for you it could be your
craving in regard to it your hatred
towards them trying to get rid of it
thinking while they're doing this they
shouldn't be doing this basically trying
to control the circumstances that are
disagreeable
without recognizing that actually
fundamentally they're not in your
control and you're responsible for lack
of that knowledge which then generates
more craving so you just keep revolving
around so instead of trying to exactly
yeah that's when people don't see the
well they don't see the root of
suffering so they think the suffering is
the the circumstances around them so
then they try to address every single
instance every example every issue every
person to talk to
everything disagreeable put away I mean
that's that's usually what people rather
revolve around
yeah it's endless cuz it's me supplied
it's not applied where the problem is
which is which is craving yeah
so you're basically trying to solve your
suffering by at a completely wrong place
where the suffering isn't